Mss.Rec.180 Mss.Rec.180
American Philosophical Society
Karok language recordings
1989
Mss.Rec.180
American Philosophical Society
12.0 Tape(s)
Elicited Karok words and phrases, with occasional anecdotes and conversation about Karok social life and customs.
12 sound cassettes (8 hr., 52 min.): analog, 1 7/8 ips, stereo.
Howerton, Stella
Macaulay, Monica Ann
Super, Violet
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Presented by Monica Macaulay in 1994 (Acc. 1994-131r). This material was recorded with the assistance of a Phillips Fund grant.
Related Archival Materials
Transcripts and notes from the recording session are available in the Phillips Fund Collection (Mss.497.3.Am4).
Karok Indians--Social life and customs; Karok language; Sound recordings
- Audio recordings
  - Elicitation of miscellaneous words, 1989-07-12; 01-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:24:12; Macaulay, Monica Ann; Super, Violet
    Scope and Contents note
    Elicited Karok words, with occasional anecdotes and conversation about Karok social life and customs.
    Existence and Location of Originals note
    This file is a compressed, digitized version of the original. The APS Library maintains the original format (Audiocassette) as well as an uncompressed digitized version of this recording.
    California; Karok Indians--Social life and customs; Karok language
  - Elicitation of miscellaneous words, 1989-07-12; 01-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:24:13; Macaulay, Monica Ann; Super, Violet
  - Elicitation of miscellaneous words, possessives, verb forms, 1989-07-12; 02-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:24:18; Macaulay, Monica Ann; Super, Violet
    Elicited Karok words and grammar, with occasional anecdotes and conversation about Karok social life and customs.
  - Elicitation of miscellaneous words, possessives, verb forms, and kinship terms, 1989-07-12; 02-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:24:14; Macaulay, Monica Ann; Super, Violet
    Elicited Karok words and phrases, with occasional anecdotes and conversation about Karok social life and customs.
  - Elicitation of miscellaneous words and phrases, with description of preparing acorns, 1989-07-12; 03-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:24:08; Macaulay, Monica Ann; Super, Violet
    Elicited Karok words and phrases, with occasional anecdotes and conversation about Karok social life and customs. Includes lengthy description in Karok and English of preparing and cooking acorns.
    Acorns as food; California; Karok Indians--Social life and customs; Karok language
  - Elicitation of terms for seafood, weather, counting, and parts of the body, 1989-07-12; 03-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:23:34; Macaulay, Monica Ann; Super, Violet
    California; Human body--Terminology; Karok Indians--Social life and customs; Karok language
  - Elicitation of words for plants and animals, 1989-07-13; 04-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:24:03; Macaulay, Monica Ann; Super, Violet
    California; Karok Indians--Social life and customs; Karok language; Plants--California, Northern
  - Elicitation of words for plants and animals, and miscellaneous adjectives, 1989-07-13; 04-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:24:05; Macaulay, Monica Ann; Super, Violet
  - Elicitation of miscellaneous words and grammar, 1989-07-13; 05-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:24:05; Macaulay, Monica Ann; Super, Violet
    Elicited Karok words and grammar, with occasional anecdotes and conversation about Karok social life and customs. Includes some words for plants and animals. Grammar includes "best ___" and "nothing but ____" constructions and superlative adjectives.
  - Elicitation of miscellaneous adjective forms, 1989-07-13; 05-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:23:47; Macaulay, Monica Ann; Super, Violet
    Elicited Karok adjectives, with occasional anecdotes and conversation about Karok social life and customs. Includes superlative adjectives, locatives, adjectival noun suffixes, and "-less" and "without" forms.
  - Elicitation of miscellaneous words and phrases, 1989-07-14; 06-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:24:06; Macaulay, Monica Ann; Super, Violet
  - Elicitation of words for animals, plants, and natural phenomena, 1989-07-14; 06-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:24:07; Macaulay, Monica Ann; Super, Violet
  - Elicitation of words for animals and plants, and miscellaneous verbs, 1989-07-14; 07-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:24:11; Macaulay, Monica Ann; Super, Violet
  - Elicitation of verbs, 1989-07-14; 07-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:20:19; Macaulay, Monica Ann; Super, Violet
    Elicited Karok verbs, with occasional anecdotes and conversation about Karok social life and customs.
  - Story of why the eel has no bones, and elicitation of miscellaneous words, 1989-07-14; 08-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:24:15; Macaulay, Monica Ann; Super, Violet
    Story of how eel lost his bones, followed by elicited Karok words, with occasional anecdotes and conversation about Karok social life and customs.
    California; Eels--Folklore; Karok Indians--Folklore; Karok Indians--Social life and customs; Karok language
  - Elicitation of words for plants, animals, and parts of the body, 1989-07-14; 08-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:24:08; Macaulay, Monica Ann; Super, Violet
    California; Human body--Terminology; Karok Indians--Social life and customs; Karok language; Plants--California, Northern
  - Elicitation of verbs, 1989-07-14; 09-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:16:43; Macaulay, Monica Ann; Super, Violet
    Elicited Karok verbs and miscellaneous words, with occasional anecdotes and conversation about Karok social life and customs.
  - Elicitation of words for animals and insects, 1989-07-17; 10-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:23:59; Howerton, Harry; Howerton, Stella; Macaulay, Monica Ann
  - Elicitation of miscellaneous words, "Bigfoot Story," and story of a female doctor, 1989-07-17; 10-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:23:57; Howerton, Stella; Macaulay, Monica Ann
    Elicited Karok words, with occasional anecdotes and conversation about Karok social life and customs, plus a story about local Bigfoot sightings and a story about a female Karok doctor who healed an eye ailment.
    California; Karok Indians--Folklore; Karok Indians--Medicine; Karok Indians--Social life and customs; Karok language; Sasquatch
  - Discussion of names of local tribes, and elicitation of words for parts of the body and names of plants, 1989-07-17; 11-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:23:59; Howerton, Stella; Macaulay, Monica Ann
    California; Human body--Terminology; Indians of North America--California; Karok Indians--Social life and customs; Karok language; Plants--California, Northern
  - Elicitation of names of plants and trees, 1989-07-17; 11-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:13:13; Howerton, Stella; Macaulay, Monica Ann
  - Elicitation of names of plants and verbs, 1989-07-18; 12-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:23:58; Howerton, Stella; Macaulay, Monica Ann
  - Elicitation of verbs, 1989-07-18; 12-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:23:57; Howerton, Stella; Macaulay, Monica Ann